The man who tried to cheat the devil.
The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus is a adventure,
fantasy, mystery film directed by Terry Gilliam.
After a carnival troupe saves his life, a man agrees to help its immortal
leader collect five souls and win a bet with the devil.
Doctor Parnassus, played by Christopher Plummer.
Valentina, played by Lily Cole.
Tony, played by Heath Ledger.
Anton, played by Andrew Garfield.
Percy, played by Verne Troyer.
Devil, played by Tom Waits.
The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus is a 2009 fantasy film directed by
Terry Gilliam and written by Gilliam and Charles McKeown.
The film follows a travelling theatre troupe whose leader, having made a bet with the Devil, takes audience members through a magical mirror
to explore their imaginations and present them with a choice between self-fulfilling enlightenment or gratifying ignorance.
The film stars Heath Ledger, Christopher Plummer, Verne Troyer, Andrew Garfield, Lily Cole, Tom Waits, Johnny Depp, Colin Farrell, and
Jude Law, though Ledger's death one-third of the way through filming caused production to be temporarily suspended.
Ledger completed most of the movie's runtime, and then his role was recast with Depp, Law, and
Farrell portraying transformations of his character as he travels through a dream world.
The film is Ledger's final performance; it was dedicated
to him and co-producer William Vince.
Its world premiere was during the 62nd Cannes Film Festival, out of competition.
The film, which cost $30 million to make, grossed more than $60
million in its worldwide theatrical release.
It received mostly positive reviews from critics.
It was nominated for two Academy Awards.
The first was Best Art Direction with art directed by Dave Warren and Anastasia
Masaro, and set decorated by Caroline Smith; it lost to Avatar.
The second was Best Costume Design with costumes designed by
Monique Prudhomme; it lost to The Young Victoria.
The film explores themes of circus, immortality, elderly,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is mind_bending.